

Andrés Felipe Sierra Álvarez

BSc. Chemical Engineer

- Sincelejo, Sucre.
- info@andresfsierra.com
- +57 300 842 6467
- @andresf-sierra
- @andresf-sierra

About me

Chemical Engineer academic experience in the fields of research, dynamic and steady-state simulation of physico-chemical processes, process optimization and data analysis. My skills include the use of tools such as Aspen Hysys, Aspen Plus, Python, GAMS, MATLAB and Excel. I am currently under formation as a Data Scientist in order to add value to my areas of engineering performance. I am characterized by speaking, public assertive communication, implementation of ideas and teamwork.

Languages

Spanish · native

English · intermediate

Interests

Programming, read sci-fi and music.

Work Experience

Costumer Service and Sales Agent

Merke Hogar

Remote 2022 - Today Advice and customer service through the Keybe (IA) platform.

 Management of national shipments from the Effi platform.

 Preparation of orders on the default platform of E-Commerce, Shopify.

Academic Consultant

Logros Staff

Pamplona 2021 - 2021

Co-Founder

AIChE UniPamplona

Pamplona 2019 - 2020

- Interdisciplinary consultant focused on teaching support and collaboration.
- Consulting and verification of educational material.
- Audit of documents and educational modules.
- Organization of academic and cultural enrichment events.
- Networking management with international chapters.
- Social Media Manager.

Education

2022 BSc. Chemical Engineer

University of Pamplona

- IV International Symposium on Chemical Engineering UniPamplona (Poster, 2021).
- Theoretical characterization of data science and artificial intelligence techniques applied in the field of materials science and engineering.

2021 Certificate in Chemical Engineering Special Topics

University of Pamplona

- Sustainable Materials Science
- Renewable Energies: Current and Future Perspective
- Industrial Process Corrosion
- Advanced Excel for Chemical Engineers
- Process Simulation with Aspen Plus V11
- Environmental Management ISO 14001:2015
- Occupational Health and Safety

2021 Certificate in Data Analysis and Machine Learning

with Python

University of Antioquia

- Data manipulation, data visualization, descriptive statistical concepts.
- Creation of Machine Learning algorithms using tools such as: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn.

Additional studies

2021 International Seminar on Engineering and its Applications
University of São Paulo

2021 IV International Symposium on Chemical Engineering 'Innovation and Development of Chemical Processes' University of Pamplona

2021 Procesa 2021: 3rd AlChE Colombia Student Regional Conference

University of America



Andrés Felipe Sierra Álvarez

BSc. Chemical Engineer

- Sincelejo, Sucre.
- info@andresfsierra.com
- +57 300 842 6467
- @ @andresf-sierra
- @andresf-sierra

About me

Chemical Engineer academic experience in the fields of research, dynamic and steady-state simulation of physico-chemical processes, process optimization and data analysis. My skills include the use of tools such as Aspen Hysys, Aspen Plus, Python, GAMS, MATLAB and Excel. I am currently under formation as a Data Scientist in order to add value to my areas of engineering performance. I am characterized by speaking, public assertive communication, implementation of ideas and teamwork.

Languages

Spanish · native

English · intermediate

Interests

Programming, read sci-fi and music.

- 2020 Problem Solving Techniques in Process and Bioprocess Engineering with MATLAB
 - Escuela Superior Politécnica del Litoral (ESPOL)
- 2019 III National Symposium of Chemical Engineering 'Catalytic, Electrochemical and Clean Energy Processes' University of Pamplona
- 2016 Il National Symposium of Chemical Engineering 'Innovation and Development of Industrial Processes' University of Pamplona
- 2015 Process Simulation using Aspen HYSYS Central University of Venezuela

Courses

- 2022 Datacademy (Bootcamp)
 - Platzi
- 2021 Python: Basic, Intermediate and Advanced
- 2021 Public Speaking

Core skills

| Public Speaking | English |
|-----------------------|-------------------|
| • • • • • • • • • | •••••• |
| Programming in Python | Aspen HYSYS |
| | • • • • • • • • • |
| Aspen Plus | CES EduPack |
| ••••• | •••••• |

Achievements and volunteering

2021 Highest Grade in Undergraduate Work

University of Pamplona

 With my degree work entitled "Theoretical characterization of data science and artificial intelligence techniques applied in the field of materials science and engineering" I obtained the maximum grade for a degree work (5.0).

2021 Campus Rep

Platzi Campus Rep Program

- Member of the first generation of the Campus Rep program, where I was selected as a Speaker in order to bring tools to micro-communities to improve their professional development.
- Meetups about "Professional Profile Management with LinkedIn" and "Basic Python for Chemical Engineers".
- 47% of the participants in the Meetups obtained certificates for at least one course on the Platzi platform.

2021 Ignite Speech

Platzi CONF

 During the Platzi CONF development, I presented an Ignite on "How is Data Science contributing to Materials Science?"